All right, everybody.
So thank you.
Oh, it's a great crowd.
Thank you so much.
It's very exciting to be here.
I am Caroline Matthews, I'm an applied AI architect from
Anthropic, and I'm here today to talk about building with
agentic coding agents in Microsoft Foundry.
So first, how did we get here?
So software development has really been shifting, as many of
you I'm sure are aware, from just writing the code
or doing auto complete to actually having agents that write
all of your code for you.
And I'm going to start, this is actually kind of
a history lesson at this point with how quickly things
are moving.
So with Anthropic, you're seeing the six generations of our
Frontier models over the last 18 months.
And what we're looking at is the suite bench verified
metric, which is a coding metric related to GitHub issues
and requests, being able to do about 500 of those
and actually get them to the point that they're ready
to go to production.
And you can see the massive improvements we've had in
terms of code development from 49 all the way up
to 87.6.
So this is this metrics actually kind of saturated.
We pretty well solved coding when you look at it
from this metrics perspective.
But a couple other things that are really important is
the long running.
So you see that last little on the left hand
or right hand side there.
The 14 1/2 hours is 1 of the longest recorded
sessions where we were still able to get good accuracy
and we're getting way beyond that.
This was just for a benchmark, but think about that.
14 1/2 hours of being able to let your agentic
code run.
So not just 30 minutes, not just 5 minutes that
we've all seen, but actually letting it run for hours
or even days to be able to complete tasks and
tool use.
We're getting super clever.
Not by we, but the models are getting very clever
about what tools they can use and how they use
them.
And all of this is available on Foundry, which is
really exciting because you get that Frontier Intelligence, but you
get all of the built in safety and governance that
comes with the Anthropic models.
But you get everything with enterprise in terms of our
back and privacy and compliance.
And it's integrated with your Microsoft stack anyway and it
just helps you get from pilot to production faster.
And just to talk, we have exciting news most of
you have probably heard, but a week ago we actually
released our most recent model, which is Opus 4.8 that
is available and that is our Frontier Intelligence.
So this is the most capable model for your truly
challenging problems.
So this could be where accuracy is very important.
This is a long running those things where you need
something that can really look over a long horizon.
Opus 4.8 is for that, but don't forget the other
models in the catalog.
So Sonnet 4.6 is really also very capable, but it
is the better cost alternative in terms of being able
to write, especially like coding tasks, it's going to do
amazing at those.
So we actually kind of recommend look at Sonnet and
start there.
And then if you need to, you can move up
to an Opus, but that's a great way to manage
your costs.
And then Haiku, don't count that out.
Haiku is our fast model.
It's extremely good for tasks like summarization and classification.
So anytime you have that low latency where you need
to be able to get something done at high volume
and low latency, especially consider Haiku.
And the great thing is it's the same prompting strategy,
it's the same safety, All those everything that was built
into the model with the constitutional AI, all of that
is still available.
So you can just redirect between the models.
All right, So with that, I'm going to talk today
about the frontiers of agentic coding because everyone's been doing
this and we're starting to really kick the tires.
And there's four areas where we see these are kind
of the edges where we think these are the things
that might hold us back.
And if we can push those edges out, those are
truly the frontiers to where we can unlock more and
more value with the agentic coding.
So the first one is what agents are allowed to
touch.
So this is how often do you have to be
there directing it and telling it what to do.
The next one is how will your agent know when
it's right?
This is again very important because we can't just be
looking line by line and and reviewing every single PR
ourselves.
That just doesn't scale.
So we've got to be able to enable the agentic
coding solutions to be able to check themselves what agents
can perceive.
Again, being able to use text, they're brilliant at that,
and they can look at a DIF and understand what's
happened with the code.
But to really unlock that power, we need to give
it more, more tools.
Essentially being able to perceive and work the way that
humans work, so they can better understand what's happening with
the things they're building.
And then when and where the agents run, Can we
keep it running?
Can it continue on its own?
So right now I have demos for each of these
frontiers.
I want to show you how we can start to
push those edges out and do this.
And I'm actually going to start with a the last
demo.
So give me just one second.
What I'm going to do is I'm actually going to
set up a somewhat long running task that's going to
get us going to begin with.
So what I've done, I've just got clock code open,
nothing special here.
And I'm going to kick it off with a task
that we're going to let it execute while we are
talking.
And what we're going to do is we're going to
create an arcade game.
And I think the gentleman that were here before me,
they may have also done that.
But what I'm going to do that's a little bit
different is something called dynamic workflows.
I don't actually have it in the presentation quite yet,
but I wanted to touch on it because this is
something that's new with Opus 4.8 just released last week,
like we'd said.
But this is a way to really start working with
those sub agents and such that are out there.
So I've kicked it off.
I've told it that to build the game, and then
we're going to go off and we're going to do
some other things while it works.
So let me pop back in too.
So the first frontier that I spoke about switching gears
back to that is how much do I need to
be involved?
And this is kind of relevant to what we're doing
right now is not having to review absolutely everything, but
only reviewing the most important things.
And the trick was we all have had this happen
where we had to, you know, kick something off.
And we went and got a coffee and came back
and it had asked us something while we were away.
And it asked us again.
It asked us again.
I'm actually about to demonstrate that.
So you'll get to see it live if you haven't.
But the way that this was handled was what's called
will dangerously skip permissions, which is about as comfortable as
that sounds.
It's very creepy.
You don't want to do that.
And everyone will tell you don't do this, but if
you have to.
So we have a new answer for that.
And again, this is to really push those frontiers.
So we now have auto mode.
So auto mode has a classifier that sits between your
requests and the models.
So it lets you have that ability to let it
run.
And it's going to be smart about what it allows.
So if it's going to read a file, if it's
going to run a test case, things like that, that
aren't really risky, it'll go for it.
But if there's still something that's run this random bash,
you know, something that could be more destructive or risky,
it will let you know.
And this is where we're seeing, you know, it's not
perfect yet.
We get really great with what it allows you to
do the the 0.4% false positive rate.
So we're less annoying.
And actually the just to be clear, the over eager
actions is when it has allowed something that you might
have preferred it ask.
So we're still working on it.
It's in research preview, but it's a huge step up
from what we were seeing.
So I'm going to show that to you just real
quickly.
I'm going to do like a before and after.
So right now I have regular cloud code up.
One thing to note here, I haven't set anything special
in terms of the way it's going to react.
And I'm going to do just a real quick I
wanted to add an endpoint to a fast API app
that I have going.
So I'm going to go ahead and click it.
Like I said, now I'm going to go off and
get coffee, assuming I'll come back and this is done.
And then what's really going to happen, unfortunately in just
a second is it's going to come up and go,
wait a minute.
Is it OK if I edit this file even though
I told it to?
That's what's in the prompt.
I told it to do it.
I have to tell it it's OK.
And then it needs to update the read me as
well.
So now I have to make sure that that's going
to be OK.
And then it's going to need to run a test
and I have to make sure that the anyway, so
you get the the drift.
So we have to go through all of these steps
and I become the bottleneck.
The human is actually keeping the agent from being able
to perform what's relatively simple tasks.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm going
to do rewind, a very cool thing in Cloud Code,
and I'm going to go back to where we were
before.
So just pretend like we're starting all over.
We're going to go back to where we were.
The files have been reset.
I'm back at my original prompt, but I'm going to
switch to auto mode now.
So you can see just down there on the screen
that yellow auto mode that's there.
And so now when I run it, we're actually going
to get the exact same results.
Nothing special there, but I'm not going to touch it.
I'll walk over here and we won't even be able
to see.
I won't be needed to do anything at all at
this point.
And so this is where we really get to that.
Hey, you can walk away from your desktop.
You could go to a meeting and come back and
you're actually going to have your work complete.
And that's what we want to see with Agenta coding,
right?
Is it can do it by itself, but within bounds
of being somewhat safe.
So that's our first frontier.
So the next one, how do you know or how
does the agent know that it's right?
So the quality control is what's critical here.
So we want to be able to use AI agents
to review the AI generated code.
That's really the way that we're going to be able
to scale, but we need to be able to do
it in a way that's well safe again, so we
can trust it and we know it's going to work.
And so in this case, the example we have here
is we looked at a case study where we had
16 parallel agents working across 100 and 1000 lines of
code to build AC compiler.
And it, well, it cost a lot.
It took a ton of sessions.
It was, well, a bit of a failure.
And so here's what we figured out is, and this
is where the entire concept of how to do this
agentic programming is we needed to have an agent that
could judge, not the agent that wrote the code.
We need a separate agent that's going to judge the
code.
And the overall process is we actually have a planner
that's going to decompose the task.
That's one agent.
We have a generator that's going to write all the
code, and then we're going to have an evaluator that
can look back on what was generated and understand if
that really suits the needs.
And in this case, we had what's GCC, which is
a way to know that this compiler essentially either the
code matches what was compiled or it doesn't.
So it's a very simple one.
And obviously not all use cases are like that, but
what we want to seriously encourage is that you put
a lot of time, effort, and research into building that
evaluator.
So that's where the time should be spent because that's
what's going to open up your being able to generate
more and more code.
So even if you don't have a perfect GCC type
of situation to judge, you can generate and you can
build the tests and build out a way to evaluate
your code and do that first.
That should be your top priority before you actually start
coding.
And so now again, I'm going to show you.
So this time what I'm going to do is we
are going to move over to what's called the Oracle.
So the Oracle is our evaluator and we're going to
use that.
And I'm going to on the left hand side here
I have the two, the split terminal.
The first thing I'm going to show is we are
going to build a very simple task or function that's
going to do, it's called bill split.
So essentially I have my friends and we've gone to
dinner and we need to split our bill and I
want you to run a little write a function that
will do that for us.
And so it's going to build it notice in auto
mode.
So I don't have to really think about it very
much.
And what it's going to build initially, as you can
see here, is it has it knows that it's not
ideal, but it's basically going to drop the sense.
So we're going to show a reviewer.
So again, this is a completely separate agent now on
this right hand side that's going to review what was
built by our generator and it's going to come back
with some advice.
And the advice is actually quite good because what we're
seeing is like the basics of this will work, but
you really could handle this a better way.
And so what's happening now is it wrote its own
test case and you can see that it failed.
So without me really having to tell it to do
much other than be adversarial, be difficult, look at that
code that was generated and figure out what's wrong.
So essentially just tell your reviewer to be as tough
as it can be and then it's going to come
back and say, yeah, you could have done this better.
And so now that we can see what our judge
thought of our results, we can go back over to
our writer and tell it that that the reviewer gave
it some advice and we're going to get it to
then update its code.
So you can you get the gist here.
But remember that evaluator, the judge, that's very important.
Do that first and then you can do whatever you
want with your code and it gives you that safety
blanket of this is already already ready to be tested.
All right, so that was the Oracle.
Now, what agents can perceive, This one's pretty exciting in
terms of becoming much more realistic about what we can
do.
So as I mentioned, we can read a DIF and
we can see what's happened when we look at code
and just read the code itself.
But being able to see what you see is critical.
And so here's a couple of very recent things with
the clod models that are available.
So first, being able to use the browser.
So this is clod in Chrome.
So this is a real Chrome, not just a headless
scrape.
So it's able to actually walk, walk through and see,
you'll see this in just a moment how it can
work with the code.
And even going beyond that, we have computer use, which
lets you go out into the machine.
And so again, this is where you can get much
closer to being able to, if you have an iOS
app, you can create a simulator, be able to run
it, and it can see what's happening and be able
to make adjustments based on that.
So for this demo, I'm actually going to show this
in Foundry and we're going to do a pen test.
And the reason I want to talk about this in
particular is a very latest one of the releases is
our ability to handle high resolution images by our, I
mean Claude, I shouldn't take credit.
So Claude, Opus 4.8 can handle a much larger size
of resolution than it has been able to in the
past.
And so the example what we've seen happen with this
is Expo that does penetration testing, they were able to
go from Opus 4.6.
They had about a 58% success rate with a Gentic
pen testing.
They got up to a 98% with that visual acuity
that came from the increase in the ability to have
these high resolution images.
And So what I'm going to show here is I've
set up a little prompt, I've set up a cloud
Opus 4.8.
This is the exact same model that I've been showing
all along, but it's in Azure Foundry and I've given
it some instructions about being a security engineer and I
wanted to evaluate some of these some things that I've
seen in a suspicious looking screen.
So let me show you my screen.
All right, So I'm going to pop this up and
hopefully everyone can see it.
I'm going to leave it here for I'm going to
do like just I'll do like 5 seconds.
Everybody look at it and see if you can identify
any risks that you would be concerned about looking at
this screen if this popped up while you were there.
All right, so you've had five seconds.
So what I'm going to do is I am going
to go back over to Foundry and I am going
to ask Foundry or I'm actually asking the cloud model
in Foundry.
I want it to review these.
And so I'm going to tell it, this is a
screenshot from an app and I want it to just
do exactly what you and I just did where we
took a look at it, give it a few seconds
and see what it comes back with.
So I've just added that screenshot and here's what we'll
see.
All right, so 3.4 seconds.
This is how long it took, and I think it's
actually just going to take longer for it to render
because I've run this a few times so I can
see it.
But from that one screen, how many of you were
able to find something?
Did you see something on the screen that made you
nervous?
One person.
Good.
You must be our pen tester.
Well, that's great.
So we did much better than we all did because
we didn't find any of the security risks.
But you can see what Claude was able to do.
And again, the point here is there was nothing on
the screen that said secrets or hey, password here.
There was nothing that was obvious.
Claude was able to do reasoning over that, so it
could ingest the image, be able to understand what was
on it, but then apply it to find all of
these security risks that were essentially in this application that
we've been running.
So again, just being able to have that additional level
of perception is one of the key ways to really
push the agent agentic frameworks.
And then last, so when and where agents run, so
we've been talking about this where we're expanding between minutes
to where we can really run for long periods of
time.
So what we're talking about with this is that you
can work on whatever surface you want to be on.
Like I said, you could kick it off on your
terminal, you could go to a meeting, you could approve
a prompt that comes in on your phone because there's
still some prompts that we want to approve.
There's still things that we need to check on.
So all of that could be done and then you
go back to your desktop and you've completed your work.
We have things like loops, being able to use scheduled
tasks, again, being able to be hands off so you
can let the agents run, pick up tasks, do what
they need to do as they need to do it,
and then also work in parallel.
And so these things like ultra plan, where you can
really go deep and make it do it, a really
significant plan.
You can even speak to it.
So that's what voice is for.
If anyone's tried that yet, it's really great.
It just helps it be a little bit faster for
you to interact.
So these are all the things that we're doing to
push those frontiers.
So a Gentek work can truly run on its own,
but still have you there to guide it.
So while we were talking, if you remember, I kicked
that demo off at the very beginning.
So we're going to go back over and take a
look and hopefully we'll have finished.
And if it hasn't, I have a backup, of course.
Yay, it finished.
All right, So what we're seeing here is the demo
has gone through.
And the one thing I want to really point out
here is we have used workflows.
So I mentioned that dynamic workflows, which is just a
really clever way that you can now manage sub agents.
So I'm going to show you that first.
So you see, we have this slash workflows command now.
And what this brings up is the different agents that
were created.
So we had three different agents that were asked to
design an arcade game for us.
And I'm just going to click through and see.
So you can see kind of what's happening here.
So the first one designed an arcade game, it's called
Neon Drift.
Our second agent said that it would try this, but
it found Pulse Runner.
It's already given it to us before it says.
And then we have Neon Ascent.
So these are three different designs for arcade games that
it came up with.
So then we have a different type of a judge.
Oops, sorry.
So we have a different judge that's a picker.
So this picker agent decided which of those designs it
wanted to move forward with, and it decided that it
wanted Neon Ascent is what we're going to have.
So it built it.
I won't go into that as much.
And then you can see where it tested it.
So 4 agents were spun up to test it.
And all of this has been happening just while we've
been talking.
So I didn't do anything special here.
I literally just said build an arcade game and don't
talk to me about it very much because I'm busy.
And so you can see it went through and it
did great testing.
It actually did open it in the browser.
It's a popped over here.
So you guys didn't see it, but it's actually did
do a lot of these things that we've been talking
about where it looks at the village visual Polish on
a projector because I told it it's going to be
seen up on a projector.
So it needs to consider that when it's deciding and
and designing its arcade game, what it's going to do.
And so we did all of this and then it
found a couple issues and it actually fixed them as
well.
So again, all of this has happened in the 15
or so minutes that we've been sitting here without very
much interaction from me at all.
And now I will show you the game.
I don't think I have sound, but there we go.
Clearly I need to learn how to use my own
game, but you can see again that it actually was
able to create all of this, including the visuals.
There is some sound.
All of that was done just with a couple of
lines of code and being able to use the dynamic
workflows.
And so that brings us to that was our final
frontier.
And I just want to kind of wrap up here
is, you know, we don't want to remove humans entirely.
That's never going to be the goal here.
But the goal is to have humans that are evaluating
and looking at the things that are most important.
So the things that are risky, the things that have
a really high value, any of those things is where
the humans are.
But we can use the agentic coding and we can
use it in amazing ways as we continue to push
these frontiers of what makes coding a little bit more
human.
And that's everything.
Thank you.